Change can be scary.
Hotel Transylvania: Transformania is a animation,
comedy, family film directed by Derek Drymon.
When Van Helsing's mysterious invention, the "Monsterfication Ray," goes haywire, Drac and his
monster pals are all transformed into humans, and Johnny becomes a monster.
In their new mismatched bodies, Drac and Johnny must team up and race across the globe to
find a cure before it's too late, and before they drive each other crazy.
Johnny (voice), played by Andy Samberg.
Mavis (voice), played by Selena Gomez.
Ericka (voice), played by Kathryn Hahn.
Van Helsing (voice), played by Jim Gaffigan.
Wayne (voice), played by Steve Buscemi.
Wanda (voice), played by Molly Shannon.
Hotel Transylvania: Transformania is a 2022 American animated monster comedy film directed by Derek Drymon
and Jennifer Kluska and written by Amos Vernon, Nunzio Randazzo, and Genndy Tartakovsky.
Produced by Sony Pictures Animation, it is the fourth installment in the Hotel Transylvania film franchise, and stars the voices of Andy Samberg, Selena Gomez, Kathryn Hahn, Jim
Gaffigan, Steve Buscemi, Molly Shannon, David Spade, Keegan-Michael Key, Brian Hull, Fran Drescher, Brad Abrell, Asher Blinkoff, Tyler "Ninja" Blevins and Zoe Berri.
The film follows Dracula and his son-in-law Johnny as they travel to South America to locate a
crystal that can reverse a transformation spell before its effects become permanent.
Originally scheduled for theatrical release in the United States on October 1,
2021, the film’s release was cancelled due to the COVID-19 pandemic.
Sony Pictures sold distribution rights to Amazon Studios for $100 million.
The film was released on Amazon Prime Video on January 14,
2022, and received mixed reviews from critics.
A fifth film is in development.
The film explores themes of monster, vampire, transformation,
aftercreditsstinger, duringcreditsstinger.
The tone is lighthearted.